<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An act for the graunt of one entier subsidie by the temporaltie</title>
            <title>Public General Acts. 1615</title>
            <author>Ireland.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1615</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 87 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 18 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A04079</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 14133</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S101339</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99837155</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99837155</idno>
            <idno type="VID">1465</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A04079)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 1465)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 991:08)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An act for the graunt of one entier subsidie by the temporaltie</title>
                  <title>Public General Acts. 1615</title>
                  <author>Ireland.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 15 [i.e. 16], [1] leaves   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Imprinted by Iohn Franckton printer to the Kings most excellent Maiesty,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Anno 1615.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Numerous misfoliations; foliation deduced from signature collation.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A-E⁴ (E4 blank).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Finance, Public --  Ireland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="frontispiece">
            <pb facs="tcp:1465:1"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:1465:1"/>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>decorative border</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>AN Act for the graunt of one entier Subſidie by the Temporaltie.</p>
            <p>DVBLIN. Imprinted by Iohn Franckton Printer to the Kings moſt excellent Maieſty Anno 1615.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="Act">
            <pb facs="tcp:1465:2"/>
            <head>An Act for the graunt of one entier Subſidy by the Temporaltie.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>His your Maieſties Realme of <hi>Ireland</hi> moſt dread and gratious Soueraigne hath in former times beene ſubiect to ſo many miſeries, as that it hath beene a continuall burthen to the Crowne of <hi>England</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out yeelding any retribution or returning of any commodity or profitt to the ſame. And albeit infinit Treaſures haue beene from time to time expended in and vppon this Kingdome, yet did it neuer thereby become more rich and wealthy, but conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nued in want and penurie, as it was before: The true cauſe whereof did ariſe from the great and long diſcentions and trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles which did waſte and depopulate the whole Land, made all poſſeſſions vncertaine, and diſabled the Subiects to im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prooue the commodities of the ſame: But foraſmuch as ſince the beginning of your Maieſties moſt happy Raigne, all the cauſes of warre, diſcention and diſcontentment, are taken away by the rooting out of many wicked and vngratefull Traytors, by receauing all the Iriſhry into your gratious Protection, by ſetling of your Subiects eſtates in their Lands, by your Commiſſions for Surrendors, and defectiue Titles, by ſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring their liues, as well by generall as particular Pardons, by remitting many great arrears of Rents meane profits, and forfeitures, by confirming and enlarging the Priuiledges of your Cytties and Townes Corporate, by eſtabliſhing the Circuits and viſitations of Iuſtice throughout the Kingdome: And laſtly by the Plantation of <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>lſter</hi> with <hi>Brittiſh</hi> Colo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, your Maieſtie now being in the abſolute and peaceable poſſeſſion of this your Vineyard, and hauing cleered it from
<pb facs="tcp:1465:3"/>the thornes and bryers of Rebellion, fenced it as well with the Law as with the Swoord, &amp; planted it with ſo many Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uill Subiects of <hi>England</hi> and <hi>Scotland,</hi> may now iuſtly expect ſome fruite thereof: And therefore wee your Maieſties moſt loyall and louing Subiects aſſembled in this preſent Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment moſt gratefully acknowledging that wee haue receaued from your Maieſtie theſe ineſtimable benefits before expreſſed, doe with all duety &amp; humble affection preſent vnto your High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nes one entyer Subſidy, moſt humbly beſeeching your Maie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtie to accept thereof, as the firſt fruites of this your poore Kingdome of <hi>Ireland:</hi> and to that end wee humbly beſeech your Maieſtie that it may be enacted.</p>
            <p>And be it enacted by the Lords Spirituall and Tempo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall and the Commons in this preſent Parliament aſſembled, and by the authority of the ſame, that your Highnes, your Heires and Succeſſors, ſhall haue and receaue one entyer Subſidy to bee rated, taxed leuied and payd at two ſeue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall and equall payments of euery perſon Spirituall and Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porall, of what eſtate or degree hee or they be, according to the Tenour of this Act in manner and forme following.</p>
            <p>That is to ſay, as well that euery perſon borne within this Realme, or other his Maieſties Dominions, as all and euery Fraternity, Guild, Corporation, Myſterie, brotherhood and Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty corporated or not corporated within this Realme, or other his Maieſties Dominions being worth three poundes, for euery pound as well in Coine, and the value of euery pound that euery ſuch perſon, Fraternity, Guild, Corporation, Myſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, brotherhood and Commonalty, corporate or not corporate, hath of his or their owne, or any other to his or their vſe: As alſo Plate, ſtocke of Marchandiſe, all manner of Corne, and Graine, houſholdſtuffe, and of all other goods mooueable as well within this Realme as without, and of all ſuch ſummes of money as to him or them is or ſhalbe owing: whereof hee or they truſt in his or their conſcience ſurely to bee payed except and out of the premiſes deducted ſuch ſummes of money as he or they owe, and in his or their conſciences intendeth truely to pay. And except alſo the apparell of euery ſuch perſon, their Wiues and Children belonging to their owne bodies, ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing Iewels, Gould, Siluer, Stone and Pearle ſhall pay to and for the ſaid Subſidy in two ſeuerall payments two ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings eight pence of euery pound, that is to ſay, ſixteene pence of euery pound at euery of the ſaid payments: And alſo euery alien and Stranger, borne out of the Kings obeyſance, as well
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:1465:3"/>Denizen as others inhabiting within this Realme, of euery pound that hee or they ſhall haue in Coine, and the value of euery pound in Plate, Corne, Graine, Marchandiſe houſhould<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtuffe, or other goods, Ieweſts, Chattels, mooueable or vnmon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ueable, as is aforeſaid as well within this Realme as with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out, &amp; of all ſummes of money to him or them owing, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of he or they truſt in his or their conſcience to be paid, except and out of the ſame premiſes deducted, euery ſuch ſumme or ſu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mes of money, which he or they doe owe, and in his or their conſcience or conſciences intend truely to pay, ſhall pay to and for the ſaid Subſidie in two feuerall payments fiue ſhillings and foure pence of euery pound, that is to ſay, two ſhillings eight pence of euery pound, at euery of the ſaid payments: And alſo that euery Alien, and Stranger borne out of the Kings Dominions, being Denizen or not Denizen, not being contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>butory to any the Rates aforeſaid, and being of the age of ſea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uen yeares or aboue, ſhall pay to and for the ſaid Subſidy, eight pence for euery Poll at two ſeuerall payments, that is to ſay foure pence for euery Poll at euery of the ſaid pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments: and the maſter or hee or ſhee with whome the ſaid Alien is or ſhalbe abyding at the time of the taxation or taxa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions thereof, to bee charged with the ſame for lacke of pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment thereof.</p>
            <p>And be it further enacted by the authority aforeſaid, that euery perſon borne vnder the Kings obeyſance, and euery Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration, Fraternity, Guild, Miſtery, Brotherhood &amp; Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty corporate or not corporate, for euery pound that euery of the ſaid perſons, and euery Corporation, Fraternity, Guild, Miſtery, Brotherhood, &amp; Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>monalty Corporate or not Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate, or any other to his or their vſe hath in Fee-ſimple, Fee-tayle for tearme of life, tearme of yeares by execution, ward<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhipp, or by coppie of Court Roll, of &amp; in any Honors, Caſtles, Mannors, Lands, Tenements, Rents, Seruices, Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Annuities, Fees, Corrodies or other yearly profits of the yearly value of twenty ſhillings, as well within auncient demeaſne, and other places priuiledged as elſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>where, and ſo vpward ſhall pay to and for the ſaid Subſidy at two ſeuerall payments foure ſhillings of and for euery pound, and euery Alien Denizen or not Denizen borne o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of his Maieſties obeyſane<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> in ſuch caſe to pay to and for the ſaid Subſidy, at two ſeuerall equall payments eight <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>llings of euery pound: and that all ſummies to bee preſented and chargeable by this Act either for goods and debtes, or either of them, or for lands
<pb facs="tcp:1465:4"/>and Tenements, and other the premiſes, as is in this Act contained, ſhalbe at euery of the ſaid payments ſet, and taxed after the Rate and proportion according to the true meaning of this Act, Lands and Tenements, chargeable to the twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth part of the Clergy, and yearly wages due to Seruants, for their yearely ſeruice (other then the Kings Seruants, ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king yearely wages of fiue poundes or aboue onely excepted, and forepriſed: And that all Plate, Coyne, Iewells, goods Debts, and Chattels perſonals, and all Lands, Tenements, and other the premiſes as aforeſaid, being in the rule and cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtodie of any perſon or perſons, to the vſe of any Corporation, Fraternity, Guild, Miſtery, Brotherhood, or any Commonaltie being Corporate or not Corporate, bee and ſhalbe rated ſet, &amp; charged by reaſon of this Act, at the value certified by the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſenters of that certificate of euery pound in goods and debts, as is aboueſaid: And for euery pound in Lands, Tenements, Annuities, Fees, Corrodies, and other yearely profits as is a foreſaid: And the ſu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mes that are aboue rehearſed ſet, &amp; taxed, to be leuied and taxed of them that ſhall haue ſuch goods in cuſtodie or otherwiſe charged for lands as is before expreſſed: And the ſame perſon or perſons, and body corporate, by autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of this Act ſhalbe diſcharged againſt him or them, that ſhall or ought to haue the ſame at the time of the payment or deliuery thereof, or at his otherwiſe departure from the cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy or poſſeſſion of the ſame (except and alwaies forpriſed from the charge and Aſſeſment of this Subſidy, all Goods, Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, Iewels &amp; Ornaments of Churches, or Chappels which haue beene ordained and vſed in Churches or Chappels for the honor and ſeruice of Almighty God. And the firſt payment of the ſaid Subſidy ſhalbe by the authority aforeſaid, taxed, ſeſſed, and rated according to this Act: In euery County, Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rony, Cantred, Citty, Borough, Towne and euery other place within this Realme of <hi>Ireland,</hi> before the firſt day of <hi>Septem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber</hi> next comming which ſhalbe in the yeare of our Lord God one thouſand ſixe hundred &amp; fifteene: And the ſecond payment of the ſaid Subſidy ſhall bee by the authority aforeſaid taxed, ſeſſed, and rated according to this Act in euery County Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rony, Cantred, Citty, Borough, Towne, and euery other place within this Realme of <hi>Ireland,</hi> before the firſt day of <hi>March,</hi> which ſhalbe in the ſaid yeare of our Lord God one thouſand ſixe hundred and fifteene, and the particular ſummes of euery County, Barony, Cantred, Citty, Borough, Towne, or other places aforeſaid, with the particuler names of ſuch as are or
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:1465:4"/>ſhalbe chargeable for and to the firſt payment of the ſaid Subſidy to bee taxed and ſet by the Commiſſioners for the ſame to bee limitted, or two of them at the leaſt, with the names of the High Collectors, and in the ſame forme ſhalbe certified into the Kings Exchecquer, before the firſt day of <hi>October,</hi> which ſhalbe in the yeare of our Lord God, one thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand ſixe hundred and fifteene, and the particular ſummes of euery Countie, Barony, Cantred, Cyttie, Borough, Towne or other places aforeſaid, with the particular names of ſuch as are or ſhalbe chargeable for and to the ſecond payment of the ſaid Subſidy to bee taxed and ſet by the Commiſſioners for the ſame to bee limitted, or two of them at the leaſt, with the names of the High Collectors, and in the ſame forme ſhalbe certified into the Kings Exchecquer before the firſt day of <hi>Aprill,</hi> which ſhalbe in the yeare of our Lord God, one thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand ſixe hundred and ſixteene: And the ſaid ſummes in forme aforeſaid to bee taxed to and for the firſt payment of the ſaid Subſidy, ſhalbe payd in one entier ſumme into y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Kings Receipt of his Exchecquer aforeſaid, to the vſe of our ſaid Soueraigne Lord, at or before the firſt day of <hi>December,</hi> which ſhalbe in the ſaid yeare of our Lord God, one thouſand ſixe hundred and fifteene, and the ſaid ſummes in manner and forme aforeſaid, to bee taxed, to and for the ſecond payment of the ſaid Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidy, ſhalbe paid in one entier ſumm einto the Receipt aforeſaid, to the vſe aforeſaid, at or before the firſt day of <hi>Iune,</hi> wich ſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>be in the yeare of our Lord God, one thouſand ſixe hundred and ſixteene, and the ſummes aforeſaid of and for the ſaid Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidie, ſhalbe taxed, ſet, aſked, and demaunded, taken, gathered, leuied, and payd, to the vſe of our ſaid Soueraigne Lord, his heires and ſucceſſors, in forme aforeſaid, as well within the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties, Franchiſes, Sanctuaries, auncient Demeaſnes, and others whatſoeuer places, exempt or not exempt, as with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out. Any graunt, Charter, Preſcription, Uſe, Libertie, or Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome, by any letters Patents, or other priuiledges, preſcrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, or allowance of the ſame, or whatſoeuer other matter of diſcharge, to the contrary heretofore made, vſed, graunted or obtained notwithſtanding.</p>
            <p>And it is further enacted by the authority of this preſent Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liame<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t that euery ſuch perſon as well ſuch as be borne vnder the Kings obeyſance, as euery other perſon ſtranger borne, Denizen or not Denize<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> inhabiting within this Realme which at y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> time of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame Aſſeſſings or taxatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>s, or of euery of the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to be had or made ſhalbe out of this Realme, &amp; haue goods, Chattels, la<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ds or Tene<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ments,
<pb facs="tcp:1465:5"/>Fees, or Annuities or other profits within this Realme ſhalbe charged and chargeable for the ſame by the certificate of the inhabitants of the place, where ſuch Goods, Chattels Lands, Tenements or other the premiſes then ſhalbe, or in ſuch other place, where ſuch perſon or perſons, or his or their factors, Deputy or Atturney, ſhall haue their moſt reſorte vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to within this Realme in like manner as if the ſaid perſon were or had beene at the time of the ſaid Aſſeſſing within this Realme: And that euery perſon abyding or dwelling within this Realme or without this Realme, ſhalbe charged or chargeable to the ſame Subſtdy graunted by this Act, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding and after the Rate of ſuch yearely ſubſtance or value of Lands, or Tenements, Goods, Chattels and other the premiſes, as euery perſon ſo to be charged ſhalbe ſet at the time of the ſaid Aſſeſſing or taxation vppon him to be made and none otherwiſe.</p>
            <p>And bee it further enacted by the authority aforeſaid, that for the Aſſeſſing and ordering of the ſaid Subſidie to bee duely had the Lord Deputie or other cheefe Gouernour of this Realme for the time being with th'aduiſe of the Lord Chauncellor, the Vice-Treaſurer, the Lord Cheefe Iuſtice of his Maieſties cheefe place, the Lord Cheefe Iuſtice of his Maieſties Court of Common pleas, the Lord Cheefe Baron of his Maieſties Court of Exchequer, and the Maieſter of the Rolls for the time being, or any two or moe of them, ſhall or may name and appoint of and for euery Countie or Sheire within this Realme, as alſo of and for euery Citty and Towne being a County of it ſelfe, ſuch and ſo many Perſons as they ſhall thinke conuenient to bee Commiſſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners of and in the ſaid ſeuerall Counties Citties or Townes And aliſo the ſaid Lord Deputy or other Cheefe Gouernour with th'aduiſe aforeſaid, in like manner may name and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point of euery other ſuch Bourough and Towne Corporate within this Realme as they ſhall thinke requiſite Sixe, Fiue Foure, Three, or Two, of the Head Officers and other honeſt Inhabitants of euery of the ſaid Citties, Boroughes and Townes Corporate according to the number &amp; multitude of the people being in the ſame, the which Perſons if any ſuch be therevnto named of the ſaid Inhabitants of the ſaid Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roughes, and Townes Corporate not being Counties of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelues ſhallbe toyned and put in as Commiſſioners with the perſons named for euery ſuch County or Counties as the ſaid Boroughes, and Townes Corporate not being Counties
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:1465:5"/>by reaſon of their dwelling in the ſame, ſhall not take vppon them, nor none of them, to put any part of their Commiſſion in execution, for the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes, out of the ſaid Citties, Bouroughes, and Townes-corporate wherein they bee ſo named onely, nor to execute the ſaid Commiſſion within the Cittie, Bourough, or Towne-corporate where they bee ſo dwelling, but at ſuch daies and times as the ſaid other Commiſſioners, for the ſame Sheire or Countie, ſhall therevnto limitt and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point within the ſaid Cittie, Bourough or Towne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corporate, not being a Countie, whereof they bee ſo named, and not out of ſuch Cittie, Bourough, or Towne: And in that manner to bee ayding and aſſiſting, with the ſaid other Commiſſioners in and for the good executing of the effect of the ſaid Commiſſion, vppon pame of euerie of the ſaid Commiſſioners ſo named, for euerte ſuch Cittie, Bourough, and Towne-corporate, not being a Countie, to make ſuch Fine as the ſaid other Commiſſioners in the Commiſſion of and for the ſame Sheire or Countie ſo named, or three of them at the leaſt, ſhall by their diſcretion, ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t and certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie into the Kings Exchequer, there to bee leuied to the vſe of the Kings Maieſtie, in like manner as if ſuch or like ſummes had beene ſet and rated vppon euery ſuch perſon, for the ſaid Subſidie, the which Commiſſioners ſo named of, and for the ſaid Citties, Bouroughes, and Townes, not being Counties, and onely put into the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, by reaſon of their dwelling in the ſame, ſhall not haue any part of the portion of the Fees and Rewardes of the Commiſſioners, and their Clerkes in this Act, afterwardes ſpecified and allowed: And the ſaid Lord Chancellor of this Realme for the time being, ſhall make and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of the Court of the Chauncerie vnder the great Seale ſeuerall Commiſſions: That is to ſay, for euery Shire, or Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie, and for each Cittie, Towne, and Brough vnto ſuch perſon and perſons, as by his diſcretion, or any of the other with him before named, and appointed, as is before re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hearſed, ſhalbe thought ſufficient for the Aſſeſſing and
<pb facs="tcp:1465:6"/>and leauying of the ſaid Subſidy in all Shires &amp; places accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the true meaning of this Act, which Commiſſion for the firſt payment of the ſaid Subſidy ſhalbe directed, and deliuered to the ſaid Commiſſioners, or to one of them before the firſt day of <hi>Iuly,</hi> which ſhalbe in the yeare of our Lord God one thouſand ſixe hundred and fifteene, and the Commiſſion for the ſecond payment of the ſaid Subſidy ſhalbe directed and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liuered to the ſaid Commiſſioners, or to one of them before the firſt day of <hi>Ianuarie</hi> then next following, which ſhalbe in the ſaid yeare one thouſand ſixe hundred and fifteene, and to eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rie of the ſaid Commiſſions ten Scheduls containing in them the Tenour of this Act ſhalbe affiled, by the which Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion the Commiſſioners in euery ſuch Commiſſion named ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to this Act, and as many of them as ſhalbe appointed by the ſaid ſeuerall Commiſſions ſhall haue full power and au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority to put th'effect of the ſame Commiſſion in execution: And that by the authority of this Act, after ſuch Commiſſion to them directed they may by their aſſents, and agreements ſeuer themſelues for th'execution of their Commiſſion in ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uerall Baronies, Cantreds, Hundreds, Townes, Pariſhes, and other places within the limits of the ſaid Commiſſion, in ſuch forme as to them ſhall ſeeme expedient to bee ordered, and betweene them to bee communed and agreed vppon ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Tenour and effect of the Commiſſion to them therein directed.</p>
            <p>And bee it alſo enacted by the authority of this preſent Parliament that the Commiſſioners, and euery of them which ſhalbe named limitted and appointed, according to this Act to bee Commiſſioners in euery ſuch Shire, or County, Citty, Towne, Borough, or any other place, and no other, ſhall truly effectually and diligently for their part execute th'effect of this preſent Act according to the Tenour thereof, in euery behalfe, and no otherwiſe by any other meanes without omiſſion, fauour, dread, malice, or any other thing to bee attempted or done by them or any of them to the contrary thereof. And the ſaid Commiſſioners or as many of them as ſhalbe appointed by the ſaid Commiſſion, and none other for the execution of the ſaid Commiſſion and Act, ſhall for the taxation of the firſt payment of the ſaid Subſidy before the tenth day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> which ſhalbe to the ſaid yeare of our Lord God one thouſand ſixe hundred and fifteene: And for the taxation of the ſaid ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond payment of the ſaid Subſidy ſhall before the tenth day of <hi>February</hi> which ſhalbe in the ſaid yeare of our Lord
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:1465:6"/>God one thouſand ſixe hundred and fifteene by vertute of the Commiſſion deliuered vnto them in forme aforeſaid direct their ſeuerall or ioynt precept or precepts vnto eight, ſeauen, ſixe, fiue, foure, three, or two, as for the number of the inhabitants ſhalbe requiſite of the moſt ſubſtantiall, diſcreete, and honeſt perſons inhabitants to bee named by the ſaid Commiſſioners, or by as many of them as ſhalbe appointed by the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of and in the Baronies, Cantreds, Hundreds, Wards, Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes, Townes, and other places as well within liberties, franchiſes, and places exempted as without within the limits of the Shires, Counties, Cittyes, Townes, Boroughes and other places within the limits of their Commiſſion, and to the Conſtables, ſubconſtables, Baylifes, &amp; other like Officers and Miniſters of euery of the ſaid Baronies, Cantreds, Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreds, Townes, Wards, Pariſhes and other places aforeſaid as to the ſaid Commiſſioners, and euery number of them, or vnto three or two of them by their diſcretion in diuiſion ſhall ſeeme expedient. Straightly by the ſaid precept, charging and commaunding the ſaid inhabitants, Conſtables and other Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers aforeſaid, to whom ſuch precept ſhalbe ſo directed, to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare in their proper perſons before the ſaid Commiſſioners or ſuch number of them as they ſhall diuide themſelues accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Tenour of the ſaid Commiſſion, at certaine daies and places by the ſaid Commiſſioners or any other number of the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> as is aforeſaid, within Citties, Boroughes, or Townes corporate or without in any other places as is aforeſaid, by their diſcretion ſhalbe limitted therevnto to doe and accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſh all that to them on the part of the Kings Maieſtie ſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>be enioyned touching this Act: commaunding further by the ſaid precept, that hee to whoſe hands ſuch precept ſhall come, ſhall ſhew and deliuer the ſame to the other inhabitants or Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers named in the ſame precept, and that none of them faile to accompliſh the ſame vppon paine of forty ſhillings to be for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited vnto the Kings Maieſtie.</p>
            <p>And it is further ordained by the authority of this preſent Parliament, that at the ſaid day and place prefixed and limitted in the ſaid precept, euery of the ſaid Commiſſioners then being within this Realme and hauing no ſufficient excuſe for his ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence at the day and place prefixed for that part, wherevnto hee was limitted, ſhall appeare in his proper perſon: And there the ſame Commiſſioners being preſent, or is many of the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> as ſhalbe appointed by the kings Maieſties Commiſſion, ſhall call or cauſe to be called before them the ſaid inhabitants and Officers
<pb facs="tcp:1465:7"/>to whome they haue directed their ſaid Precepts, and which had in commaundement there to appeare, by vertue of the ſaid Precept. And if any perſon ſo warned, make default, vnleſſe hee then bee letted by ſickneſſe or lawfull excuſe, and that let, then bee witneſſed by the oathes of two credible per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, or if any appearing, refuſe to ſerue in forme following, then euerie ſuch perſon ſo making default or refuſing to ſerue, ſhall forfeit to the Kings Maieſtie fortie ſhillings, and ſo at euerie time appointed by the ſaid Commiſſioners for the ſame taxation, vntill ſuch time the number of euery ſuch perſons haue appeared and certified (in forme vnder-written, euerie of them ſo making default, or refuſing to ſerue) ſhall forfeite to the Kings Maieſtie fortie ſhillings. And vppon the ſame appa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance had, they ſhalbe charged before the Commiſſioners, by all conuenie<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t wayes and meanes, (other then by corporall oath) to enquire of the beſt and moſt value of the ſubſtance of eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry perſon dwelling and abyding within the limits of the pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces that they ſhalbe charged with, and of other which ſhall haue his, or their moſt reſorte vnto any of the ſaid places, and chargeable, with any ſumme of money by this Act, of the ſaid Subſidie, and of all other things requiſite touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſaid Act, and according to the intent of the ſame: And therevppon as neere as it may bee, or ſhall come to their knowledge, truely, to preſent and certifie before the ſaid Commiſſioners, the names and ſurnames, and the beſt and vt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termoſt ſubſtance and values of euerie of them, as well of Lands, Tenements, and other Hereditaments, poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſions, and profits, as of goods, Chattels, Debts, and other things chargeable by the ſame Act, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any concealment, loue, fauour, affection, dreade, or malice, vppon paine of forfeiture of fiue pounds or more, to bee taxed, extracted, and leuied in forme as hereafter in this preſent Act ſhalbe limitted or ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, and therevppon the ſaid Commiſſioners ſhall openly there reade, or cauſe to bee reade vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to them the ſaid Rates in this Act mentioned, and openly declare the effect of their charge vnto them, in what manner and forme they ought and ſhould make their certificate according to the Rates &amp; ſu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mes thereof aforeſaid, &amp; of all manner of perſons
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:1465:7"/>as well of Aliens and Strangers, Dentzens or not Denizens inhabiting within this Realme, as of ſuch perſons as be borne vnder the Kings obeyſance chargeable to this Act, and of the poſſeſſions, Goods, and Chattels of Fraternities, Guilds, Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porations, Brotherhoods, Myſteries, Commonalties, &amp; other as is aboue ſaid, and of perſons being in the parts beyond the Seas, hauing Goods and Chattels, Lands or Tenements within this Realme as is aforeſaid, and of all Goods being in the cuſtody of any perſon or perſons to the vſe of any other as is aboueſaid, by the which information and ſhewing the ſaid perſons ſhould haue ſuch plaine knowledge of the true in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent of this preſent Act, &amp; of the manner of their certificat that they in the ſame perſons ſhall haue no reaſonable cauſe to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſe them by ignorance. And after ſuch charge and the ſtatute of the ſaid Subſidy, and the manner of the ſaid certificate to be made in writing conteining the names, and ſurnames of euery perſon, and whether hee bee borne without the Kings obey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſance, or within, and the beſt value of euery perſon in euery degree, as well of the yearely value of Lands and Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and of ſuch like poſſeſſions and profits, as of the value of Goods and Chattels, Debts and euery thing to their cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate requiſite and neceſſary to them declared the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners there being ſhall by there diſcretions appoint and limit vnto the ſaid perſons another day and place to appeare before the ſaid Commiſſioners and charging the ſaid perſons that the meane time ſhall make diligent inquiry by all waies and meanes of the premiſes: And then, and there euery of them vppon paine of forfeiture of forty ſhillings to the Kings Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſtie to appeare at the newe prefixed day and place there to certifie vnto the ſaid Commiſſioners in writing according to their ſaid charge and according to the true intent of the ſaid graunt of this preſent Subſidy, and as to them in manner aforeſaid hath beene declared and ſhewed by the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners at which day and place ſo to them prefixed, if any of the ſaid perſons make default or appeare, and refuſe to make the ſaid certificate, that then euery of them ſo offending to forfeit to the Kings Maieſtie forty ſhillings, except there be a rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable excuſe of his default by reaſon of ſicknes or otherwiſe by the oaths of two credible perſons their witneſſed, and of ſuch as appeare ready to make certificate as aforeſaid the ſaid Commiſſioners there being, ſhall take and receaue the ſame certificate and euery part thereof, and the names, values and ſubſtance of euery perſon ſo certified. And if the ſaid Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>miſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners
<pb facs="tcp:1465:8"/>ſee cauſe reaſonable, they ſhall examine the ſaid preſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters thereof, and therevppon the ſaid Commiſſioners, at the ſaid daies and place, by their agreement amongeſt themſelues, ſhall fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> time to time their ope<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ly prefixe a day at a certaine place or places, within the limits of their Commiſſion, by their diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion for their further proceeding, to the ſaid Aſſeſſing of the ſame Subſidy: And therevppon at the ſaid day of the ſaid certificate as is aforeſaid taken, the ſame Commiſſioners, ſhall make their Precept or Precepts, to the Shiriffs, Vnderſhi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffs, Conſtables, Sub-conſtables, Bailiffs or other Officers of ſuch Shires, Baronies, Cantreds, Hundreds, Townes, or other places aforeſaid, as the ſame Commiſſioners ſhalbe of, compriſing and containing in the ſaid Precept the names and ſurnames of all perſons preſented before them in the ſaid cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate, of whome if the ſaid Commiſſioners, or as many of them as ſhalbe therevnto appointed by the Kings Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, ſhall then haue vehement ſuſpect, to bee of more greater value or ſubſtance in Lands, Goods, Chattels or ſummes of money, owing to them, or other ſubſtance before ſaid, then vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pon ſuch perſon or perſons, ſo certified and ſpecified as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, the ſame Commiſſioners ſhall make their Precept or Precepts directed to the Shiriffs, Vnderſhiriffs, Conſtables, Bailiffs, or other Officers, commaunding the ſame Shiriffs, Vnderſhiriffs, Conſtables, Bailiffs, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> other Officers, to whom ſuch Precepts ſhalbe directed, to warne ſuch perſons, whoſe names ſhalbe compriſed in the ſaid Precepts, at their man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions, or to their perſons that the ſame perſons named in ſuch Precepts, and euery of them, ſhall perſonally appeare before fore the ſaid Commiſſioners, at the ſame newe prefixed day and place, there to bee examined by all waies and meanes, (other then by corporall oath) by the ſaid Commiſſioners, of their greateſt ſubſtance and beſt value, of all and euery ſumme, and ſummes of money, owing to them, and other what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoeuer matter concerning the premiſes, or any of them, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to this Act. At which day and place ſo prefixed, the ſaid Commiſſioners then and there being, or as many of them as ſhalbe therevnto appointed by the Kings Commiſſion, ſhall cauſe to bee called the ſaid perſons, whoſe names ſhalbe com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſed in the ſaid Precept as is aforeſaid, for their examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion: And if any of thoſe perſons, which ſhalbe warned as is aforeſaid, to bee examined, which at any time after the war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, and before the prefixed day, ſhalbe within ſuch place where hee may haue knowledge of his ſaid apparance to bee
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:1465:8"/>made, make default and app<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap> not, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a reaſonable cauſe, or elſe a reaſonable excuſe by the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>at he s<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>d the dible perſons, before the ſaid Commiſſioners be truly alleadged fork is diſcharge, that then euerie or them ſo making default, to be taxed and char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged to the Kings Maieſtie, with and at the double ſumme of the rate, that he ſhould, or ought to haue beene ſet at, for and after the beſt value of his lands or ſubſtance vppon him certified, if hee had appeared by the diſcretion of the ſaid Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>miſſioners there be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, which Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>miſſioners ſhall trauell with euery of the other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons then and there appearing, whoſe names ſhalbe expreſſed in the ſaid Precept or Precepts, &amp; in whome any behement ſuſpect was, or ſhalbe had in torme aforeſaid, by all ſuch waſes, &amp; meanes as they can (other then by corporall oath) for y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> better knowledge of their beſt value, either in hereditaments, or poſſeſſions, or elſe in goods and debts, &amp; there vppon ſhall haue power and authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, by vertue of this Act, according to their diſcretions to inlarge and increaſe the taxations of ſuch perſons, as they ſhall ſo finde, by due examination, to be of greater value or ſubſtance in lands, or goods, then they were preſented at, and that euery ſpirituall perſon at euery of the ſaid taxations, of the ſaid Subſidy, ſhalbe rated, and ſet, according to the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>le aboueſaid, of &amp; for euery pound that the ſame ſpirituall perſon for and other, to his vſe hath by diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent, bargaine, purchaſe in Fee ſimple, Fee taile, tearme of life, tearme of yeares, by execution, by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſhipp, or by coppie of Court-Roll in any M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>iors, Lands, Tehements, Rents, Seruices, Offices, Fees, Cor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>od<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>es, or Hereditaments, after the true, tuſt, and yearely value thereof and according as other the Kings Maieſties Subiects, borne within this Realme bee char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged in forme abone remembred, ſo that it extend to the yearely value of twenty ſhillings, or aboue.</p>
            <p>And it is further enacted, that if the ſaid taxors or aſſeſſors, ſhall not duely behaue themſelues in their inquirſe, taxation, aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſment, or certificate, but ſhall affectionally <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> ly demeane themſelues in that behalfe, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners ſhall by their conſiderations, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> worthy of puniſhment, for not doing <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, that then foure or more of the Commiſſioners <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, for the ſame Subſidy, ſhall haue power <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> either to charge the ſaid aſſeſſors vpon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> the better ſerutre aforeſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> tions to tax<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> &amp; ſet vpon euery of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> meanors in that behalfe ſuch <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> good, ſo that it exceed not the ſumme of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>, and the ſame
<pb facs="tcp:1465:9"/>fine or peine at their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Court of Exche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer, euery which fiue to taxed &amp; ſet by foure of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſaid Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>miſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or more, being eſtreated with the Schedule, &amp; Bookes of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> limit, ſhalbe leuied &amp; anſwered to the Kings vſe, in like manner &amp; forms to all intents &amp; purpoſes, as any otherſummes that ſhalbe taxed, &amp; become, due by vertue of this ſtatute &amp; Act of Subſidy, &amp; not in any otherwiſe or manner. And if any perſon certified, or ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, by vertue of this Act, whether he be a Commiſſioner, or other to any manner of value, doth finde himſelfe grieued with the ſame preſentment, ſeſſing or rating, and therevppon complaine to the Commiſſioners, before whome he ſhalbe called, feſſed, or taxed, or before two of them, before the ſame taxation be certified into the Court of Exchequer, that the ſaid Commiſſioners, or two of them ſhall by all waies &amp; meanes, examine particularly and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtinetly, the perſon ſo complaining vppon his oath, and other his neighbours, by their diſcretions, of euery his Lands and Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>me<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ts aboue ſpecified, &amp; of euery his goods, Chattels, and debts aboue-mentioned: And after due examinatio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> and perfect know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge thereof had, and perceaued by the ſaid Commiſſioners or two of them, which ſhall haue power by authority aforeſaid, the ſaid Comiſſioners, or two of them, to whome any ſuch complai<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t ſhalbe made, by their diſcretions vpon the oath of the ſaid perſon ſo complaining, may abate, defalke, increaſe or inlarge y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſments, according as it ſhall appeare to them iuſt, vppon the ſame examination, &amp; the ſame ſu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>me ſo abated, defalted, increaſed or enlarged ſhalbe by the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> eſtreated in forme as hereafter enſueth. And if it be proued by wittneſſes or by the parties owne confeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion or other lawful waies or meanes, within a yeare after ſuch oath made, that y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame perſon ſorated or ſworne was of any bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, or greater value in Lands, Goods, or other things aboue ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cified at the time of his ſaid oath, then the ſame perſon ſo ſworne did declare vpon his ſaid oath, that the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> euery perſon ſo offending, ſhall looſe &amp; forfeit to his Maieſtie ſo much lawful money of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> as he the ſaid perſon ſo ſworne was ſet at, or taxed to pay.</p>
            <p>And alſo it is attacked by the ſame out hority, that euery perſon to be rated and taxed as is aforeſaid, ſhalbe rated, &amp; ſet, and the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> on him ſet, to bee leuied at ſuch place where hee and his family were <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> the moſt part of the yeare next before the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> preſentment and taxation made, &amp; no where elſe. And that no Commiſſioner for this <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> ſhalbe rated or taxed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> in the Countie or other place where hee <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Commiſſioned <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>; And that if <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> perſon chargea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> at the time of the ſaid aſſeſſing happen to
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:1465:9"/>bee out of this Realme, or farre from the place where he ſhalbe knowen, then hee to bee ſet, where hee was laſt abyding in this Realme, and after the ſubſtance, value, and other pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits of euery perſon, to bee knowen by examination, certificate or other manner of wiſe, as is aforeſaid, and that the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or as many of them as ſhalbe appointed by the Kings Maieſties Commiſſion, or Commiſſions, ſhall after the rate and rates aforeſaid, cauſe euery perſon ſo to be ſet, rated, and taxed, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> rate of the ſubſta<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>te, &amp; value of his la<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ds, goods Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, and other profits chargeable by this Act, whereby the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſt, or moſt beſt ſumme, or ſu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mes, according to his moſt ſubſtance by reaſon of this Act, might or may be ſet or taxed. And that eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry perſon taxed in any County or place, other then where he and his family were reſident, for the moſt part of the yeare, then next before, or in any County or place, other then where he is a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner for the Subſidy, if he be a Commiſſioner, vppon certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficate, made to the ſaid Court of Exchecquer, vnder the hands &amp; ſeales of two Commiſſioners for the ſame Subſidy, in the ſame Cou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ty or place where ſuch perſon, &amp; his family were reſiant, for the moſt part of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> yeare next before, or where he is a Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>miſſioner, for the taxation &amp; payme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame Subſidie, teſtifying ſuch his moſt reſta<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>cy, hauing a family, or being a Co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mmiſſioner, ſhalbe a ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficie<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t diſcharge for y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> taxation of that perſon in all other places &amp; of &amp; for all other ſummes of money vppon ſuch perſons ſo ſet and taxed, ſaue onely the taxation made in that County, or place from which ſuch certificate ſhalbe made as is aforeſaid, and for the ſu<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>me of money vppon ſuch perſons, there aſſeſſed, or taxed. And that ſuch certificate, without any plea, or other circumſtance, ſhalbe a ſufficient warrant, as well to the Barons and Auditor, and Auditors of the ſaid Court of Excheequer, and to all, and euerie other Officers to whome the allowance thereof, ſhall ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pertaine, paying for ſuch diſcharge and allowance, onely ſixe pence, and no more. Prouided alwaies that euerie ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, which ſhalbe rated, or taxed, according to the intent and true meaning of this Act, for payment of and to this Subſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die, for and after the yearely value of his Lands, Tenements, &amp; other reall poſſeſſions, or profits, at any of the ſaid taxations ſhall not after be ſet and rated for his goods, and Chattels, or other moneable ſubſtance at the ſame taxation, and that hee that ſhalbe ſet, charged, or taxed for the ſame Subſidy, for his goods, Charels &amp; other moueables, at any of the ſaid taxations, according to the true meaning of this Art ſhall not after be chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged, taxed or chargeable, for his lends or other reall poſſeſſions,
<pb facs="tcp:1465:10"/>and profits aboueſaid, at the ſame taxations, or any of them, nor that any perſon by any taxation bee double charged for the ſaid Subſidy, nor ſet, or taxed at ſeuerall places, by reaſon of this Act. But if any perſon happen to be double ſet, taxed, or charged either in any place, or at ſeuerall places, then he to bee diſchar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged of the one taxation &amp; charged with the other according to the meaning and intent of this Act, any thing contained in this preſent Act, to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
            <p>And that it bee ordained and enacted, by the ſaid authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of this preſent Parliament, that no perſon hauing two manſions, or two places to reſort vnto, or calling himſelfe houſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold ſeruant, or waiting-ſeruant to the Lord-deputy, or other Lord, or Lady, Maſter, or Miſtres bee excuſed vppon his ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, from the taxes of the ſaid Subſidy, in neither of the pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces where he may bee ſet or taxed, vnleſſe he bring a certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate, in writing from the Commiſſioners, where that he is ſo ſet or taxed indeede at one place: And if any perſon that ought to bee ſet and taxed to this preſent Subſidy, by reaſon of his remouing and reſorting to two places, or by reaſon of his ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that hee elſe where was taxed, or by reaſon of any priui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of his dwelling, or abyding in any place not being fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſed in this Act, or otherwiſe by his Couine or craft, or by any words, or ſayings, or otherwiſe, or if any that is a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner, or Aſſeſſor of others happen to eſcape from the ſaid taxation, for the payment of this Subſidy, and be not ſet and taxed, according to the true intent of this Act, and that prod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned by preſentme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t examination, information or otherwiſe, before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or two of them, or before the Barons of the Kings Maieſties Exchecquer, or two Iuſtices of the Peace, of the County where ſuch perſon dwelleth, then euerie ſuch perſon, that by ſuch meanes, or otherwiſe willingly by Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uin, or without iuſt cauſe, ſhall happen to eſcape from the ſaid taxations, or payments aforeſaid or any of them, and ſhall not bee rated, taxed and ſet, ſhalbe charged vppon the knowledge and proofs thereof, with &amp; at the double value of ſomuth as he ſhould might, or ought to haue beene ſet, and taxed at, by ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of this Act, and the ſame double value to bee gathered, lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uied, and payd, of his Goods and Chattels, Lands and Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, towards the ſaid Subſidy, and further to bee puni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhed according to the diſcretions of the Barons, Iuſtices, and Commiſſioners, before whome hee ſhalbe committed for his offence and deceipt in that behalfe.</p>
            <p>And hee it further enacted by the authority aforeſaid, that
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:1465:10"/>the ſaid Commiſſioners, in euery Commiſſion, which ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> or inhabit, in any County or place, within the ſimits of their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion, or the more part of them, ſhall haue full power and authority by this Art, to ſet, taxe, and ſeſſe euery other Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner ioyned with them, in euery ſuch Commiſſion and the ſaid Commiſſioners within euery diuiſion ſhall alſo aſſeſſe euery aſſeſſor within his or their diuiſion, for his or their goods, Lands, and other the premiſts as is aboue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, by the which ſaid Commiſſion, the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, to whome it ſhall appertaine, ſhall indifferently ſet, taxe, and ſeſſe themſelues, and the ſaid aſſeſſors, and that as well the ſummes vppon euerie of the ſaid Commiſſioners and Aſſeſſors ſo ſeſſed, rated, and taxed, as the ſummes made and preſented by the preſentors, as is aforeſaid, ſhal be written certified, ſet, and eſtreated, and the eſtreats thereof to be made with the other inhabitants of that part, and within the li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits of the ſame Commiſſion and diuiſion ſo to bee gathered and leauied, in like manner as it ought, or ſhould haue beene, if the ſaid Commiſſioners had not beene in the ſaid, Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion: And that all perſons of the eſtates of a Baron, or Barons, and euerie eſtate aboue, ſhalbe charged with their freeh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and value as aforeſaid, by the Lord-deputy or other Chiefe Gouernour of this Realme, with the a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eriſe aforeſaid: And they to bee charged for the ſaid ſeuerall payments of the ſaid Subſidy, after the forme of the ſaid graunt, according to the taxation aforeſaid: And the ſummie of and vppon them to bee ſet, and taxed, with the names of the Collectors appointed for the gathering, and paying of the ſame, to bee eſtreated, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liuered, and certified, at daies and places alone ſpecified, by the Lord-deputy, or other Chiefe Gouernour of the ſaid Realme for the time being, together, with other ſuch perſons as there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vnto ſhalbe named as is aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>And bee it further enacted, by the authority aforeſaid, that after the taxes, and aſſeſſes of the ſaid ſummes, vppon and by the ſaid Aſſeſſing and certificate, as is aforeſaid made, the ſaid Commiſſioners, or as many of them, as ſhalbe there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto appointed, and haue authority by the Kings Maieſties Commiſſion, ſhall with all ſpeed and without delay by their writting eſtreate the ſaid taxes thereof under their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and ſignes Mannuall, if the ſaid Commiſſioners, or as ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of them, as ſhalbe appointed at the leaſt and the ſame ſhall deliuer vnto ſufficient and ſubſtantiall thhabitants, Shiri<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>s, Vnderſhiriffs, Conſtables, Subconſtables, Bailiffs, and other
<pb facs="tcp:1465:11"/>Officers <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>yntly, of Baronies, Ca<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>treds, Hundreds, Townes, Pariſhes, and other places aforeſaid, within their limits, and other ſufficient perſons Inhabitants of the ſame, onely by the diſcretion of the ſaid Commiſſioners, with the aſſent of the High Collector. And as the place and pa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ties ſhall require, as well the particular names and ſurnames, as the remem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brance of all ſummes of money taxed, and ſet, of and vppon euerie perſon as well man as woman chargeable to this Act, Houſe-holders and other Inhabitants and dwellers within the ſaid Pariſhes, Townes and places contributory to this Act of Subſidie: By authority, of which writing and eſtreate ſo deliuered, the ſame Officers and other perſons ſo named and deputed ſeuerally<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, ſhall haue full power and authority, by vertue of this Act, immediatly after the deliuery of the ſaid writing or eſtreate, to demaund, leuie, &amp; gather, of euery perſon therein, ſpeeiſſed; the ſnmme &amp; ſummes, in the ſame writing or eſtreate compriſed, and for not payment thereof, to diſtraine the ſame perſon or perſons ſo being behinde, by their Goods and Chattels, and the diſtreſſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſo taken to keepe by the ſpace of eight daies, at the coſts and charges of the owner thereof. And if the ſaid owner, doe not pay ſuch ſumme of money, as ſhalbe leauied by authority of this. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> within the ſaid eight daies, then the ſame diſtr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſſe to be appraiſed by foure, three, or two of the Iuhabi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ts<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> where <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> diſtreſſe is taken, and alſo then to dee fould by the Conſtable or other Collector, for the payment of the ſaid muney, &amp; the ouerplus comming of the ſale and keeping there of, if any bee, to bee immediatly reſtored to the owner of the ſame diſtreſſe, which ſaid Officers and othr perſons ſo <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, to aſke, take, gather, and leauy the the ſaid ſummes, ſhall anſwere and bee charged, for the por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion onely to the l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ſigned, and limitted to bee gathered, lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uied and compriſed in the ſaid Writting of eſtreate, ſo to them as is aforeſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                  <desc>••••</desc>
               </gap>ered, to the vſe of our. Soueraigne Lord the Kings <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and his Heires and Succeſſors, and the ſaid ſumme in that writting or eſtreate compriſed, to pay vnto the High Collector or Bollectors of that place, for the collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſame, in manner and forme vnerwritten, therevn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to to<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> named and deputed. And the ſame Inhabitants and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, ſo gathering the ſame particular ſummes, for their collection thereof, ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> retaine for, euery twenty ſhillings ſo by them re<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ation and pays, two pence, and that to be allowed at the payment of their collection, by them to bee made to the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:1465:11"/>High Collector or Collectors. And <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> for the ſaid authority that the ſaid. Commiſſiones, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> part of them, as ſhall take vppon them, the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſines of the ſaid Commiſſion, ſhall for euery or the ſaid pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of the ſaid Subſidie, name ſuch ſufficient <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, which then ſhall haue and poſſeſts lands and other here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments in their owne right of the cleare <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> of twenty pounds, or goods to the value of foure <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> at the leaſt, as hee ſhalbe taxed in the Sul<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ie Booke <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> any ſuch be in the ſaid limits, &amp; for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of ſuch ſo aſſeſted, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> thoſe to bee appointed Collectors that then ſhalbe ſufficient in lands or goods neereſt to the values aforeſaid, as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> their diſcretion ſhalbe thought good in the ſeuerall Counties. Shines, Citties, Townes-corporate, and other what ſo ouer places, as well within places priuiledged as without, not being forepriſed within this Act, to bee High Collector<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>, and to haue the look<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and receipt of the ſaid ſummes ſet, and leauiable, within the Precluts, Limits, &amp; Bounds where they ſhall be ſo limi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red and appointed to bee High Coll<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>rs, and to euerie of the ſaid Collectors ſo ſeuerally <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, the ſaid Commiſſion<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>, or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of them at the leaſt, with all <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and without <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> the whole ſummè of any payment of the ſaid Subſidy be ſet, by all the limits of the ſame their. Commiſſion, or in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits as the High Collectors ſhalbe ſo ſeue<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>lly aſſig<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed, ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>alk vnder their. Seales and ſignes Mannuall, deliuer one eſtreate indented in parchment, compriſing in it the names of all ſuch perſons as were aſſigned to leauy the and particular <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> And the ſummes of euerie Ba<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ny, Contred, Hundred, Cittie, Towne, and other places aforeſaid, with the names and ſurnames of the perſons ſo chargeable according to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> thereof, made and deliuered as is <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>geſaid, and the Collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors to bee aſſigned, ſhalbe charged to anſwere the whole <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> compriſed in the ſaid eſtreate limitted to his collertion as is aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwaies, and be it enacted by the authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that the ſaid Commiſſioners hauing authority by this Act, to name and nominate the ſaid High Collectors of the ſaid Subſidy, ſhall immediatly <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> take by authority, of this <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> recogni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>es or obligations <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> ſo bee payd therefore of euery <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> med to bee High, Collectors to bee <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Kings Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ie, in the double ſumme, of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of his collection and
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:1465:12"/>to be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ade vpon ſuch condition, That is to ſay for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of the ſaid firſt payments of the ſaid Subſidie, that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Collector, his heires or executors, doe truely content and pay to the vſe of the Kings Maieſtie, his Heires and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> in the Rereipt of the ſaid Excherquer, at or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſhe ſaid firſt day of <hi>December,</hi> which ſhalbe in the ſaid yeare or our Lord God one thouſand ſixe hundred and fifteene, ſo much of the ſaid ſumme of money, allotted and appointed to his col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lection, as hee ſhall collect and gather, and content, and pay the reſidue of his collection, and charge within one moneth next after ſuch time as he hath gathered and collected the ſame re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidue, that then the ſaid recogniſances or obligations to be voyd, or elſe to ſtand in full ſtrength and vertue. And for the collection of the ſaid ſecond payment, of the ſaid Subſidy, vpon condi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, that if the ſaid Collector, his heires or executors, doe truely rontent and pay to the vſe of the Kings Maieſtie, his Heires and Su<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ſſors, in his Highnes Court of Excherqu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>, at or before the ſaid firſt day of <hi>Iune,</hi> which ſhalbe in the ſaid yeare of our Lord God, one thouſand ſixe hundred and ſixercene, ſo <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of the ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of money, alloted and appointed to his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, as her ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and gather, and content and pay the reſt one of his collection, and charge, within one moneth <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>xt-after <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> as he hath collected and gathe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red the ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> that the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the ſaid recogniſances, or obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gations to be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, or elſe to ſtand in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſtrength and vertue: which ſaid recogni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ces or obligations ſo taken, the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſiones ſhall ſecretally certifie, and deliuer into the Kings Maiſties Excherquer, with the ſeuerall certificats of the ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and rates of the payment of the ſaid Subſidy, at and by the time <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> them preſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ibed and appointed by this Act, for the ſaid certificate of the ſaid ſeueraſt raxarſons of the ſaid Subſidiſe, vpon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of forfeiture of ten pounds to the Kings Mai<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>, for euery ſuch recognifances or obligations not to certified, and that euerie ſuch Collector ſo elerted, named and ch<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>in, vpon requ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> to him made, ſhall knowledge, and make the ſaid recogniſance or obligation, vpon paine of forfeiture of twenty pounds to the Kings Maieſtie for the refuſall there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, and that the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> and Barons of the Exchecquer for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> of the ſtuerall conections of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> and times therein limitted for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> Lancell and deliuer the ſaid recog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ces or obligations, for the payment thereof, to the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lector, or Collectors, without any other warrant, and with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:1465:12"/>any F<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> to her paid for the ſame, to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, and euerie Collector <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 words">
                  <desc>〈◊◊◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the ſaid eſtreat, in parchment as is aforeſaid, ſhall haue authority by this Act, to appoint <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ies and places within the circuit of his collection, for the payment of the ſaid Subſidie to him to bee made, and thereof to giue warning by Proclamation or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, to all the Conſtables, or other perſons or Inhabitants, hauing the chargs of the particular collections within the Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ronies, Cantreds, Hundreds, Pariſhes, Townes or other places by him or them limitted, to make payment for the ſaid particular collection of euerie ſumme, as to them ſhall ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pertaine. And if at that ſame day, and place ſo limitted and prefixed by the ſaid High Collector, the ſaid Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, Officers, or other perſons or Inhabitants, as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, for the ſaid particular collection aſſigned and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed within ſuch Baronie, Cantred, Hundred, Eyttie-Towne, or other place, doe not pay vnto the ſaid high Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors, the ſumme within their ſeuerall Baronies, Cantreds Hundreds, Townes, Pariſhes and other places due and compriſed within the ſaid eſtreat thereof, to them deliuered by the ſaid Commiſſioners <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, ſome of them as is aforeſaid, or ſomuch thereof as they haue by and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>aues receaued, <hi>two pence</hi> for euerie pound, for the ſaid particular collection as is aforeſaid, alwaies thereof to bee allowed excepted and abated, that then it ſhalbe lawfull to the ſaid High Collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors and euerie of them, and to their aſſignes to diſtraine euerie of the ſaid Conſtables, Officers and other Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants, for their ſaid ſeuerall and particular collection, of the ſaid ſummes compriſed in the ſaid eſtreat, and writing there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of to them, and euerie of them as is before expreſſed, deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uered, or for ſo much of the ſame ſumme, as ſo then ſhall happen to bee gathered and leauied, and bee behinde and vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>payd by the Goods and Chattels of euerie of them, ſo being behinde and vnpaid: And the diſtreſſe ſo taken to bee kept, and appraiſed, and ſould, as is aforeſaid, and thereof to take and leauie the ſummes, ſo then being, behinde and vnpaid, and the ouerplus comming of the ſale of the ſaid diſtreſſe, if any bee to bee reſtored and deliuered vnto the owner in forme aboue remembred.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwaies, and bee it enacted by the authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that no perſon or perſons ſhalbe nominated or appointed to bee High Collector or Collectors for the ſecond payment of the ſaid Subſidie graunted by this Act, which before that time
<pb facs="tcp:1465:13"/>hath beene a Collector or Collectors, for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> payment of any p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>t of the ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> perſon or perſons ſo to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> and appointed to bee High Collector or Collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors for the ſaid ſecond payment, doe firſt ſhewe forth before h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>, or the in, by whome hee ſhalbe ſo nominated and appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted his <hi>quietus eſt</hi> for his diſcharge of his collection, before ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to his charge, vppon paine of one hundred pounds to bee paid and forfeited by him or them, that ſo ſhall nomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate, and appoint any ſuch Collector contrary to this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Act.</p>
            <p>And it is alſo by the ſaid authority enacted, that if any Inhabitants or Officers, or whatſoeuer perſon or perſons char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged, to and for the collection and Receipt, of any part or por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſaid Subſidie, by any manner of meanes, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to this Act, or any perſon or perſons, for themſelues or as keeper, Guardian, Deputie, Factor, or Arturney, of or for any perſon or perſons of any Goods, or Chattels of the owner thereof, at the tune of the ſaid aſſeſſing to bee paid, being out of this Realme, or in any other part not knowen, or of and for the Goods and Chattels of any other perſon or perſons of any Corporation, Fraternitie, Myſterie or other whatſoeuer Commonaltie being corporate or not corporate, and all per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons hauing in their rule gouernance, and cuſtodie, any Goods or Chattels, at the time of the ſaid aſſeſſings, or any of them to bee made, or which for any cauſe for and by collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion or for himſelfe, or for any other, or by reaſon that he hath the rule, Gouernance, or cuſtodie, of any Goods or Chattels of any other perſon or perſons, Corporation, Commonaltie, Fraternitie, Guild, or Myſterie, or any ſuch other like, or as Factor, Debitor or Arturney, of or for any perſon ſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bee taxed, valued, tared, and ſet to any ſumme or ſummes by reaſon of this Act, and after the taxation and aſſeſſing vppon any ſuch perſon or perſons, as ſhalbe charged with the Receipt of the ſame, happen to die, or depart from the place where hee was ſo taxed and ſet, or his Goods and Chattels bee ſo eſtoyned, or in ſuch priuie or couert manner kept, as the ſaid perſon or perſons, charged with the ſame by the eſtreats or other writing from the ſaid Commiſſioners, or as many of them as ſhalbe therevnto appointed by the ſaid Commiſſion as is aforeſaid, can nor may leauy the ſame ſumme or ſummes compriſed to th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the ſaid eſtreats, by diſtreſſe within the limits of their collection as is aforeſaid, or cannot ſell ſuch diſtreſſe
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:1465:13"/>or diſtreſſes as bee taken for any of the ſaid pa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>its, before the time limitted, to the High Collector for the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to bee made in the Kings Maieſties Receipt, then vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pon relation thereof with due examination, by the oath or exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mination of ſuch perſon or perſons, as ſhalbe charged with and for the Receipt and collection of the ſame before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or as many of them as by the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion, ſhalbe therevnto appointed, where ſuch perſon or perſons, or other as is aforeſaid, their Goods and Chattels, were ſet and taxed: And vppon plaine certificate thereof made into the Kings Maieſties Exchecquer, by the ſame Commiſſioners, as well of the dwelling place, names and ſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mes of the ſaid perſons, of whome the ſame ſummes cannot bee leauied, and had as is aforeſaid, then as well the Conſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, and other Inhabitants, appointed for the ſame particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar collection, againſt the High Collectors, as the High Collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor, vppon his accoumpt and oath, in the ſaid Exchecquer, to bee diſcharged thereof, and proceſſe to bee made for the Kings Maieſtie out of the ſame Exchecquer by the diſcretions of the Barons of the ſame Exchecquer againſt ſuch perſon his heires or executors, ſo being behinde with his payment, and ouer, that the ſame Commiſſioners, to whome any ſuch declaration of the premiſes ſhalbe made, in forme aforeſaid, from time to tune ſhall haue full power and authority, to direct their Precept or Precepts, to the ſaid perſon or perſons, charged with any ſumme, of, for, and vppon any ſuch perſon and perſons, or other as is aforeſaid, or to any Shiriffe, Steward, Bailife or other whatſoeuer Officer, Miniſter, perſon or perſons of ſuch place or places, where any ſuch perſon or perſons, ſo owing any ſuch ſumme or ſummes, ſhall haue Land and Tenements or other Hereditaments, or reall poſſeſſions, Goods and Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, whereby any ſuch perſon or perſons ſo indebted, his heires executors or aſſignes, or other hauing the cuſtodie, go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uernance or diſpoſition of any Goods, Chattels, Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, or other Hereditaments, which ought or may by this Act, lawfully bee diſtrained or taken for the ſame, hath and ſhall haue Goods, Chattels, Lands, Tenements, or other poſſeſſions, whereof ſuch ſumme and ſummes, which by any ſuch perſon or perſons, may or ought to bee leauied, be it within the limits of ſuch Commiſſion, where ſuch perſon or perſons was or were taxed, or without, in any place within this Realme of <hi>Ireland,</hi> by which Precept as well ſuch perſon or perſons ſhalbe charged to leauy ſuch money as the Officer of the place
<pb facs="tcp:1465:14"/>or places, where ſuch diſtreſſe may bee taken, ſhall haue full power and authority to diſtraine euerie ſuch perſon indebted, charged, or chargeable by this Act, or his executors or admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtrators of his goods and Chattels, his Guardians, Factors, Deputies, Leſſees, Farmers, and aſſignes, and all other perſons, by whoſe hands, or out of whoſe lands, any ſuch perſon ſhould haue, Fee, Rent, Annuitie, or other profitt, or which at the time of the ſaid aſſeſſing, ſhall haue Goods, or Chattels, or any other thing mooueable of any ſuch perſon, or perſons, being indebted, or owing ſuch ſumme, and the diſtreſſes ſo taken, cauſe to bee kept, appraiſed, and ſould in like manner, and forme as is aforeſaid, for the diſtreſſe to be taken, vpon ſuch perſons to be taxed, to the ſaid Subſidie, and being ſufficient to diſtraine within the limitts of the Collectors, inhabitants, or other Officers charged with or for the ſaid ſummes, ſo vpon them to bee taxed. And if any ſuch diſtreſſe, for non payment hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen to bee taken, out of the limits of the ſaid perſons, char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged and aſſigned, to leauy the ſame, the perſon ſo charged for the leauying of any ſuch ſummes by diſtreſſe, ſhall perceaue and take of the ſame diſtreſſe, for the labor of euerie ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon going for the execution thereof, for euerie mile that any ſuch perſon ſo laboreth for the ſame <hi>two pence:</hi> And euerie Far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer, Tenant, Guardian, Factor, or other whatſoeuer per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon being diſtramed, or otherwiſe charged for payment of any ſuch ſumme, or ſummes, or any other ſumme, by reaſon of this Act, ſhalbe of ſuch ſumme or ſummes, of him or them, ſo lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uied and taken, acquited and diſcharged at his next day of pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the ſame, or at the deliuery of ſuch Goods and Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, as hee that is ſo diſtrained, had in his cuſtodie or go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uernance, againſt him or them, that ſhalbe ſo taxed and ſet. Any graunt, or writing obligatory or other whatſoeuer matter to the contrarie made, heretofore notwithſtanding. And if any ſuch perſon that ſhould bee ſo diſtrained haue no Lands or Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements ſufficient, whereby hee and his Tenants and Far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mers may bee diſtrained, or haue aliened, eloyned, or hid his Goods and Chattels, whereby hee ſhould or might bee di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrained, in ſuch manner that ſuch Goods and Chattels ſhould not bee knowen or found, ſo that the ſumme of, or by him to bee paid in the ſaid forme, ſhall not, ne can bee conuenient<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly leauied, then vppon relation thereof to the Commiſſioners, or to as many of them, as by the ſaid Commiſſion ſhalbe there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vnto appointed, where ſuch perſon or perſons were taxed and ſet, by the oathes of him or them, that ſhalbe charged with
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:1465:14"/>the leauying and payment of that ſumme or ſummes, the ſame Commiſſioners ſhall make a Precept in ſuch manner as is aforeſaid, for to attach, take and arreſt, the body of ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons, that ought to pay the ſaid ſummes, and by this Act, ſhalbe charged with, and for the ſaid ſumme or ſummes, and them ſo taken ſafely to keepe in priſon within the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie, or other place where any ſuch perſon or perſons ſhalbe taken and attached, there to remaine without bayle or main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſe, vntill hee hath paid the ſaid ſumme or ſummes, that ſuch perſon for himſelfe, or for any other by this Act, ſhalbe chargeable, or ought to bee charged withall, and alſo for the Fees of euerie ſuch arreſt, to him or them that ſhall execute ſuch Precept, <hi>twenty pence,</hi> and that euery Officer to whome ſuch Precept ſhalbe directed, doe his due diligence and exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute the ſame, vpon euerie perſon ſo being indebted, vpon paine to forfeit to the Kings Maieſtie, for euerie default in that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>halfe, twenty ſhillings, and that no keeper of any Goale, from his Goale ſuffer any ſuch perſon to goe at large, by letting to bayle or otherwiſe to depart out of his priſon, before he hath payd his ſaid debt, and the ſaid <hi>twenty pence</hi> for the ſaid ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt, vpon paine to forfeit to the Kings Maieſtie forty ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, and the ſame Goaler, to pay to the Kings Maieſtie, the double value, as well of the rate, which the ſaid perſon ſo impriſoned, was taxed at, as of the ſaid <hi>twenty pence,</hi> for the Fees, and like proceſſe and remedy, in like forme ſhalbe graun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by the ſaid Commiſſioners, or as many of them, as by the ſaid Commiſſion ſhalbe therevnto appointed, at like infor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of euery perſon, or perſons, being charged with any ſumme of money, for any other perſon or perſons, by reaſon of the ſaid Subſidie, and not thereof payd, but wilfully with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drawen, nor the ſame leuiable within the limitts, where ſuch perſons were therevnto taxed. And if the ſumme or ſummes, being behinde and vnpaid, by any perſon or perſons as is afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, bee leauied and gathered by force of the ſaid proceſſe, to bee made by the ſaid Commiſſioners, or if in default or for lacke of payment thereof, the perſon or perſons ſo owing the ſaid ſummes of money, by proceſſe of the ſame Commiſſioners to bee made as is aforeſaid, bee committed to priſon in forme aboue ſaid, that then the ſaid Commiſſioners which ſhall ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warde ſuch proceſſe, ſhall make certificate thereof, in the ſaid Exchecquer, of that ſhalbe done in the premiſes, in the tearme next following, after ſuch ſumme or ſummes ſo being behinde, ſhalbe leauied and gathered, or ſuch perſon or perſons, for non
<pb facs="tcp:1465:15"/>payment of the ſame, comitted to priſon. And if it happen any of the ſaid Collectors, to bee aſſigned, or any Mayors, Shi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffs, Stewards, Conſtables, Bayliffs or any other Officer, or Miniſter, or other whatſoeuer perſon or perſons, to diſobey the ſaid Commiſſioners, or any of them in the reaſonable requeſt to them made by the ſaid Commiſſioners, for the execution of of the ſaid Commiſſion, or if any of the Officers, or other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons doe refuſe, that to them ſhall appertaine, or belong to do by reaſon of any Precept to him or them to bee directed, or any reaſonable commaundement, inſtance, or requeſt touching the premiſes, or other default in any apparance or collection, to make: Or if any perſon being ſuſpected, not bee indiffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rently taxed, as is aforeſaid, doe refuſe to bee examined ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Tenor of this Act, before the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, or as many of them as ſhalbe therevnto aſſigned as is aforeſaid, or will not appeare before the ſame Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, vppon warning to him made, or elſe make reſiſtance, or refuſe, vpon any diſtreſſe vpon him to bee taken, for any par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cells of the ſaid Subſidie, or committ any miſbehauiour in any manner of wiſe contrary to this Act, or committ any wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full omiſſion, or other whatſoeuer wilfull doing or miſdoing, contrarie to the Tenor of this Act or Graunt, the ſame Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, and enerie number of them aboue remembred, or two of them at the leaſt, vpon probable knowledge of any ſuch miſdemeanors, had by information or examination, ſhall and may ſet vpon euerie ſuch offendor, for euery ſuch offence in the name of afine by the ſame offendor to bee forſeited, forty ſhillings or vnder, by the diſcretion of the ſame Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners: And further the ſame Commiſſioners, and euerie num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of them, or two of them at the leaſt ſhall haue authority by this preſent Act, to puniſh euerie ſuch offendor by impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonment there to remaine, and to bee deliuered by their diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion, as ſhall ſeeme to them conuenient, the ſaid Fines (if any ſuch bee) to bee certified by the ſaid Commiſſioners that ſo aſſeſſed the ſame into the ſaid Kings Maieſties Exchecquer there to be leuied and paid by the Collectors of that part of the ſaid Subſidie, returned into the ſaid Exchecquer, to be there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with charged, with the payment of the ſaid Subſidie, in ſuch manner, as if the ſaid Fines, had beene ſet and taxed, vpon the ſaid offendors for the ſaid Subſidie.</p>
            <p>And it is alſo enacted by the ſaid authority of this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Parliament, that euery of the ſaid High Collectors, which ſhall accoumpt for any part of the ſaid Subſidie, in the ſaid
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:1465:15"/>Exchecquer, vpon their ſeuerall accoumpts to be yeelded, ſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bee allowed at euer<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> of the ſaid payments, of the ſaid Subſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die, for euerie pound limitted to his collection, whereof any ſuch. Collector, ſhalbe charged and yeeld accoumpt, <hi>ſixe pence,</hi> as par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cell of his or their charge, that is to ſay, of euerie pound there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of ſuch perſons, as then haue had the particular collection of the Townes, and other places, as is aforeſaid, ſpecified in his collection <hi>two pence,</hi> and other <hi>two pence</hi> of euerie pound thereof, euerie of the ſaid chiefe Collectors, or their accoump<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants, to retaine to their owne vſe, for their labour and charge in and about the premiſes, and <hi>two pence</hi> of euerie pound reſidne to bee deliuered, allowed and paid by the ſaid Collectors ſo being thereof allowed, to ſuch of the Commiſſioners as ſhall take vppon them the buſines and labour, for and about the premiſes, that is to ſay, euerie Collector to pay that Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioner or Commiſſioners which had the ordering of the wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings, of and for the ſaid Subſidie, where the ſaid Collector or Collectors, had their collection, for the expences for the ſaid Commiſſioners, ſo taking vppon them the ſaid buſines, and labour of their Clarks writing of the ſaid Precepts and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracts of the ſaid collections, the ſanie laſt <hi>two pence</hi> of euery pound to bee deuided amongſt the ſaid Commiſſioners, hauing regard to their labour and buſines taken by them and their ſaid Clarks, in and about the premiſes, for which part ſo to the Commiſſioners appertaining, the ſaid Commiſſioners, Sixe, Fiue, Foure, Three, or Two, or as many of them as ſhalbe therevnto appointed by the Kings Maieſties Commiſſion, and euerie of them ioyntly and ſeuerally, for his and their ſaid part, may haue his remedie againſt the ſaid Collector or Collectors, which thereof beene or might haue beene allowed by action of debt, in the which the defendant ſhall not wage his law, nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther protection, neither iniunction, or eſſoyne ſhalbe allowed, and that no perſon now being of the number of the Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of this preſent Parliament, nor any Commiſſioner ſhalbe named or aſſigned to bee any Collector or Subcollector or preſenter of the ſaid Subſidies, or any part thereof, nor any Commiſſioners ſhalbe compelled to make any preſentment or certificate, other then into the Kings Maieſties ſaid Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>checquer, of, for or concerning the ſaid Subſidie, or any part or parcell thereof: And likewiſe that no other perſon that ſhal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>be named and aſſigned to bee Commiſſioner in any place to and for the execution of this Act of Subſſdie, bee or ſhalbe aſſigned or named Head-collector, of any of the payments of
<pb facs="tcp:1465:16"/>the ſaid Subſidie, neither of any part thereof, and that euery ſuch perſon or perſons which ſhalbe named and appointed, as is aforeſaid, to bee Head-collectors of and for the firſt pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the ſaid Subſidie, and collection thereof, or of any part thereof, ſhall not bee compelled to bee Collector for the ſecond payment of the ſaid Subſidie, nor for any part thereof and the ſaid Collectors which ſhalbe aſſigned for the collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſaid Subſidie, or any part thereof, and euerie of them, bee and ſhalbe acquitted and diſcharged, of all manner Fees, Rewards, and of euerte other charges in the Kings Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſties Exchecquer or elſe where, of them or any of them by reaſon of that collection, payments or accoumpts, or any thing concerning the ſame to bee aſked: And that if any perſon re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceaue or take any Fees, Rewards or pleaſures, of any ſuch accoumptant, or vſe any vnneceſſary delay in their accoumpt that then hee ſhall forfeit vnto the Kings Maieſtie, for euerie penny or value of euerie penny or penny-worth, ſo taken fiue ſhillings, and fiue pounds to the partie grieued, for euerie ſuch delay and ſuffer impriſonment, at the Kings Maieſties plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure, and after euerie taxing and aſſeſſing of the ſaid Subſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die, as is aforeſaid, had or made, and the ſaid eſtreats there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of in parchment vnto the Collector, in manner and forme be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore rehearſed deliuered, the ſaid Commiſſioners, which ſhall take vppon them the execution of this Act within the limitts of their Commiſſion by their agreements, ſhall haue meetings together, at which meeting euerie of the ſaid Commiſſioners which then ſhall haue taken vppon them the execution of any part of the ſaid Commiſſion, ſhall by himſelfe or his ſufficient Deputie, truely certifie, and bring forth vnto the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners named in the ſaid Commiſſion, the certificate and preſentment made before him, and ſuch other Commiſſioners as were limitted with him in one limitt, ſo that the ſame cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tificate may bee accounpted and caſt, with th'other certificats of th'other limits within the ſame Commiſſion, and then the ſaid Commiſſioners and euerie number of them, vnto two at the leaſt as is aforeſaid, if any bee in life, or their executors or adminiſtrators of their goods if they then bee dead, ſhall ioyntly and ſeuerally as they were deuided in their limits, vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der their Seales by their diſcretion, make one or ſeuerall wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings indented, containing in it as well the names of the ſaid Collectors, by the Commiſſioners for ſuch collection and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counpts in the Exchecquer, and payments in the ſame Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt deputed and aſſigned, as the groſſe and ſeuerall ſummes
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:1465:16"/>written vnto euerie ſuch Collectors to receaue the ſaid Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidie, and alſo all fines amerciaments, and other forfeitures, if any ſuch by reaſon of this Act, happen to bee within the Precinct and limitt of their Commiſſion, to bee certified into the Kings Maieſties ſaid Exchecquer by the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, in which writing or writings, indented ſo to bee cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tified, ſhalbe plainely declared and expreſſed, the whole and entire ſumme or ſummes of the ſaid Subſidies, ſeuerally li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to the collection of the ſaid Collectors ſeuerally, depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted and aſſigned to the collection of the ſaid ſummes, ſo that none of the ſaid Collectors ſo certified in the ſaid Exchecquer, ſhalbe compelled there to accoumpt or to bee charged, but one<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to and for the ſummes limitted to his collection, and not to and for any ſumme limitted to the collection of his fellowes, but euerie of them ſhalbe ſeuerally charged for their part li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to their collection: And if the ſaid Commiſſioners ioyned in one Commiſſion amongſt themſelues in that mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter cannot agree, or if any of them bee not ready or refuſe to make certificate with other of the ſame Commiſſioners, that then the ſaid Commiſſioners, may make ſeuerall Indentures in forme aforeſaid, of their ſeuerall limits or ſeparations of Collectors, within the limitts of their Commiſſion vpon and in the Baronies, Cantreds, or ſuch other like deuiſions with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſaid ſeuerall limitts of their Commiſſion, as the places there ſhall require to bee ſeuered and deuided, and as to the ſame Commiſſioners ſhall ſeeme good to make deuiſions of their limitts or Collections, for the ſeuerall charges of the ſame Collectors, ſo that alway one Collector, ſhalbe charged and accoumpt for his part to him to bee limitted onely by himſelfe, and not for any ſumme limitted to the part of any of his fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowes, and the charges of euerie of the Collectors, to bee ſet and certified ſeuerally vppon them: And euerie ſuch Collec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor, vppon his accoumpt and payment of the ſumme of mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney limitted within his collection, to bee ſeuerally by himſelfe acquitted and diſcharged in the ſaid Exchecquer, without paying any manner of Fees or rewardes, to any perſon or perſons for the ſame, vppon paine and penaltie laſt aboue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, and not to bee charged for any portion of any other col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lector, and if any Commiſſioner after he hath taken certificate of them, that as is aforeſaid ſhalve lefore any ſuch Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners examined, and the ſummes rated and ſet, and the Books &amp; writings thereof being in his hands, or if any Collector
<pb facs="tcp:1465:17"/>or other perſon charged with any Receipt of any part of the ſaid Subſidie, or any other perſon taxed, or otherwiſe by this Act charged, with or for any parcell of the ſaid Subſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die, or with any other ſumme. Fine, amerciament, penaltie, or other forfeiture, happen to die before the Commiſſioners, Collectors, or other whatſoeuer perſon or perſons haue exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted, accompliſhed, ſatiſſied or ſufficiently diſcharged, that which to euerie ſuch perſon ſhall appertaine, or belong to doe according to this Act, then the executors and heires of eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rie ſuch perſon, and all other ſeiſſed of any Lands and Ce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, that any ſuch perſon being charged by this Act, and deceaſing before hee be diſcharged thereof, or any other to his vſe onely had of eſtate of inheritance, at the time that any ſuch perſon was named Commiſſioner, Collector, or otherwiſe charged with or for any manner of thing to bee done, ſatiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied or payd by reaſon of this Act, and all thoſe that haue in their poſſeſſions or hands, any Goods, Chattels, Leaſes, or other things that were to any perſon or perſons, at the time of his death, or any Lands or Tenements that were to the ſame perſons, at the time hee was, as is aforeſaid, charged by this Act, ſhalve by the ſame compelled and charged, to doe and accompliſh in euerie Caſe, as the ſame perſon ſo being charged, ſhould haue done or might haue beene compelled to doe it hee had beene <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> pla<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e life, after ſuch rate of the Lands and Goods of the ſaid Commiſſioner or Collector, as the partie ſhall haue in his hands, and if the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners for cauſes reaſonable them moueing, ſhall thinke it not conuenient to ioyne in one certificate as is aforſaid: Then the ſaid perſon or perſons that ſhall firſt ioyne together, or hee that ſhall firſt certifie the ſaid writing indented, as is aforeſaid, ſhall certifie all the names of the Commiſſioners of that Commiſſion, wherevppon ſuch writing ſhalbe there then to bee certified, with deuiſion of the Baronies, Cantreds, Hundreds, Tythings and other places, to and among ſuch Commiſſioners of the ſame Commiſſion, with the names of the ſame Commiſſioners where ſuch ſeparations and deuiſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons ſhalbe, with the groſſe ſummes of money, as well of and for the ſaid Subſidie taxed or ſet, of or within the ſaid Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ronies, Cantreds, Hundreds, Tythings or other places to him or them deuided or aſſigned, that ſhall ſo certifie the ſaid firſt writing, as of the Fines amerciaments, penalties &amp; other forfeitures, if any happen to bee within the ſame limits, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:1465:17"/>the ſame writings ſhaide certi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed, and after ſuch writing indented, which as is aforeſaid ſhalbe certified, and not con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taine in it the whole and full ſummes ſet and taxed within the limits of the ſaid Commiſſion, the other Commiſſioners of the ſame before the day of payment of the ſaid Subſidie, ſhall certifie into the ſaid Exchecquer, by their writing or writings indented to bee made as is aforeſaid, the groſſe and ſeuerall ſummes ſet and taxed within the places to them li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted, for the ſaid Subſidie, and other Fines, amerciaments, penalties, and forfeitures, with the names of the Baronies, Cantreds, Hundreds, Tythings and other places to them aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned, or elſe by their ſaid writings indented, to certifie at the ſame place before the ſame day of payment, ſuch reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able cauſes for their excuſes, whie they may not make ſuch certificate, of and for the ſaid Subſidies, Fines, amercia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and other cauſes growing or ſet, by reaſon of the cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes of their lets, or of their not certifying as is aforeſaid, or elſe in default thereof proceſſe to bee made out of the Kings Maieſties ſaid Exchecquer, againſt the ſaid Commiſſioners, and euerie of them, not making certificate as is aforeſaid, by the diſcretion of the Treaſurer and Baruns of the ſaid Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>checquer.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwaies, and bee it further enacted by the autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforeſaid, that all and euerie perſon and perſons, hauing Mannors, Lands, Tenements and other Hereditaments chargeable to the payment of the ſaid Subſidie, graunted to the Kings Maieſtie by this Act, and alſo hauing ſpirituall poſſeſſions chargeable to his ſaid Maieſtie, by the graunt made by the Cleargie of this Realme in their conuocation, and ouer this hauing ſubſtance in Goods, and Chattels, charge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able by this ſayd Act, that then if any of the ſaid perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons be hereafter charged or aſſeſſed, and taxed for the ſaid Mannors, Lands and Tenements and ſpirituall poſſeſſions, and alſo aſſeſſed charged and taxed, for his and their Goods and Chattels, that then hee or they ſhalbe onely charged by vertue of this Act, for his and their ſaid Mannors, Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments and ſpirituall poſſeſſions, or ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly for his ſaid Goods and Chattels, the beſt thereof to bee taken for the Kings Maieſtie and not to bee charged for both, or double charged for any of them. Any thing in this Act con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained to the contrarie, in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwaies, that this graunt of Subſidie or any
<pb facs="tcp:1465:18"/>thing therein contained in any wiſe extend not, to charge the Prouoſt, fellowes and ſchollers, of the Colledge of the holie Trinitie neere <hi>Dublin,</hi> nor any Mannors, Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, or other poſſeſſions, Goods, Chattells or other moue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able ſubſtance, which the ſaid Prouoſt fellowes &amp; ſchollers, or any others to their vſe, haue within this Realme of <hi>Ireland.</hi> Any thing in this preſent Act, to the contrarie in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwaies, and bee it enacted by the authoritie aforeſaid, that no Orphant or Infant within the age of twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and one yeares, borne within any the Kings Maieſties Dominions, ſhalbe charged to any payment of this Subſidy for his or her Goods and Chattels to him or her left or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queathed: Any thing in this Act contained to the contrarie notwithſtanding.</p>
            <p>Prouided neuertheleſſe, and bee it enacted by the autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritie aforeſaid that if any Alien or Stranger borne, Denizen or not Denizen, and dwelling or inhabiting within this Realme of <hi>Ireland,</hi> ſhall aſſigne or conuay ouer vnto any his or their Childe or Children borne within this ſaid Realme of <hi>Ireland</hi> any his or their Lands, Tenements, Goods and Chattels to the intent thereby to defraud the Kings Maieſtie of his ſaid Subſidie of or for the ſame, that then all and euerie ſuch Child or Children, ſo being ſeiſed of any ſuch Lands and Tenements, or poſſeſſed of any ſuch Goods or Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, ſhalbe charged and chargeable, to and with the payment of double the ſaid Subſidie for the ſame Lands Tenements, Goods and Chattels at the ſaid rates and values as Aliens and Strangers Denizens or not Deni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zens are before limitted and appointed to pay.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <pb facs="tcp:1465:18"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Imprinted at Dublin by Iohn Franckton Printer to the Kings moſt excellent Maieſtie for Ireland. Anno Domini. 1615.</hi> *(*)*  *(*)*</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
